Jesse Jia

A recent Applied Mathematics graduate motivated to make an immediate impact in this world. Possesses the technical capability of an engineer to solve complex open-ended problems while having the entrepreneurial thirst for building sustainable businesses. I have a continual passion for learning and believe that there's a greater good behind every experience. Currently, manage a travel blog (www.followingjesse.com) and a web design company (www.jessexjia.com) while working full time as a consultant.

jesse@followingjesse.com

416-737-8668



www.jessexjia.com

in linkedin.com/in/jessexjia

WORK EXPERIENCE

Implementation Consultant Delbridge Solutions

07/2019 - Present

Focused on creating a custom Corporate Performance Management (CPM) system to meet the organizational needs of all varieties of clients.

- Design optimal data models to organize existing databases using SQL and CCH Tagetik.
- Trains and consults end user how to effectively utilize the CPM solution system to build custom forms and reports.

Full Stack Web Developer & Owner JXJ Web Design

01/2018 - Present

Web design business responsible for creating web solutions including everything from design, construction development, and hosting.

- Consults clients' objective of the website and illustrates possible designs using wireframes.
- Develops a responsive layout using HTML, CSS, and JS.
- Walkthrough the server setup and hosting in the best interest of the client (shared hosting, dedicated hosting).

Data Analyst

Technische Universität Berlin

05/2017 - 09/2017

A lab focused on creating a gamified education system that educates topics to students based on various game scenarios and outcomes.

- Conducted in-depth data and statistical analysis using MATLAB. Excel. and R.
- Explored various analysis techniques to identify possible outliers and the possible rationale.
- Identified ways to optimize game results from biases while creating a fair and enjoyable experience.

EDUCATION

Applied Mathematics and Mechanical Engineering

Oueen's University

09/2015 - 04/2019

Relevant Coursework

- Probability & Statistics
- Differential Equations
- Algorithms
- Solid Mechanics
- Real & Complex Analysis
- Linear Algebra
- Control theory
- Data Structures
- Fluid Mechanics
- Coding Theory

SKILLS

MySQL

MATLAB

PROJECTS

Following Jesse (2016 – Present)

Personal blog of my life experiences around the world. (www.followingjesse.com)

Tennis Camp Markham (2018)

- Private tennis coaching business focused on on-court satisfaction.
- Coached players of with ages varying from 5 up to 65.

ShoMe - Hack Harvard (Winner) (2018)

- Visualize a network of connections between events around the world. (https://jessejia.wixsite.com/shome)
- Utilizes a modified Breadth First search written in Python to graph and identify shortest path of event connections.

EasyPark - YHacks (Finalist) (2018)

Utilizes the SmartCar API to seamlessly create a parking valet service to allow others to park your car. (https://git.io/fpP8r)

TruState - StartupBus (2018)

- Real Estate application that facilitates the selling of property without a realtor.
- Created an attractive landing page using HTML/CSS/JS to drive interests in our MVP demo. (www.trustateapp.com)

ACHIEVEMENTS

DAAD RISE Scholarship Recipient (2017)

Research in Science and Engineering in Germany. (\$7000)

Queen's University Principal Scholarship (2015 – 2016)

A renewable scholarship for up to 2 years presented to students able to maintain a minimum GPA of 3.5 in their first 2 years of study. (\$4000)

LANGUAGES

JavaScript

HTML/CSS

INTERESTS

Tennis Photography

Videography

Design

Startups

Python

Travelling

Blockchain

Trading